
[
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What structure was built during the Old Kingdom in Egypt?",
    "correct_answer": "The Sphinx",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The Temple of Queen Nzingha",
      "The Tower of Babel",
      "The Pyramids of Judah"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which of these was not an ancient Phoenician city?",
    "correct_answer": "Madrid",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Sidon",
      "Tyre",
      "Berot"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which of these was not an ancient Phoenician deity?",
    "correct_answer": "Jupiter",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Moloch",
      "Astarte",
      "Baal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Who colonized Tunisia in ancient times?",
    "correct_answer": "Phoenicians",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Philistines",
      "Pyrgamese",
      "Palmyrans"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which of these is an early period in the Bronze Age?",
    "correct_answer": "Chalcolithic",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Paleolithic",
      "Eolithic",
      "Prolithic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What word means 'of the Middle Ages'?",
    "correct_answer": "medieval",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "mediocre",
      "metal",
      "medial"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Where did the ancient Phoenicians live?",
    "correct_answer": "Phoenicia",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Portugal",
      "Phrygia",
      "Phoenix"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which was not an achievement of ancient Egyptians?",
    "correct_answer": "golf",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "medicine",
      "architecture",
      "mathematics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "The Stone Age is called that because of its:",
    "correct_answer": "abundance of stone tools",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "scarcity of stones (used as money)",
      "abundance of stone statues",
      "abundance of stone houses"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Highly respected and loved, what animal had considerable importance in ancient Egypt?",
    "correct_answer": "Cat",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Horse",
      "Deer",
      "Bear"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "The civilization of Ancient Mesopotamia grew up along the banks of two great rivers, the Euphrates and the Tigris.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization was the first to use democracy?",
    "correct_answer": "Ancient Greece",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Ancient Rome",
      "The Persian Civilization",
      "The Aztec Civilization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "The calendar of which ancient civilization is thought to have predicted the end of the world?",
    "correct_answer": "The Mayan civilization",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Ancient Greece",
      "The Chinese civilization",
      "Ancient Romans"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "The Aztecs actually called themselves the Mexica.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Aztec Empire is known for creating one of the world's first laws in history.",
    "correct_answer": "False",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "True"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Cyrus The Great is credited as the founder of the Persian civilization.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "How many of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World still exist?",
    "correct_answer": "One",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Three",
      "Five",
      "None"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "How was the ancient Roman city of Pompeii destroyed?",
    "correct_answer": "Volcano",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Flood",
      "Tsunami",
      "Drought"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Tenochtitlan was a massive capital city in Aztec.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Civilization",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What was one of the Inca cities which was situated at a height of nearly 3500 meters?",
    "correct_answer": "Machu Picchu",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Cusco",
      "Tiwanaku",
      "Ollantaytambo"
    ]
  }
]
